Today I'm going to show you exactly how
to edit viral podcast intros inside of
DaVinci Resolve. And I'm not just going
to teach you from scratch, I'm going to
break down an intro that I did that got
over 300,000 views. And I'm talking
about the Bryce Crawford and Kenneth
Copeland interview. I had the
opportunity to actually edit this, so
I'm going to show you guys exactly how I
did it all inside of DaVinci Resolve. So
let's hop straight into the video. So
we're going to break this down into a
couple of sections. So the first section
is how did I find these viral moments?
So we have six viral moments that were
said in the podcast. So what we first
have to do is figure out the best viral
moments. So how I do that is I basically
use a little bit of AI. And so how we do
that is we need to transcribe this
without having to watch the full 2-hour
interview. This is insane sauce. We're
going to right click on the clip inside
of our media pool, and we have to come
to AI tools, go to audio transcription,
and then hit transcribe. Now as you can
see, I already have it transcribed up
here. But I do want to mention that the
highlighting is an option you can do,
but I will say it's not the most
efficient idea because it doesn't come
with the timestamps, right? So to get
the timestamps, we're going to hit this
export and then we're just going to save
this uh PDF file as uh um into our
downloads. So I'm going to open up
Claude AI. I'm going to type in this
prompt, and then I'm just going to
simply add in this PDF file. So add this
in, and then as you can see, it's going
to just going to look like this, and
then we're just going to hit generate.
Basically, it's going to give us the
best parts of the of the podcast, and it
will give us the timestamps to then go
in and look at those timestamps and then
pull those clips that way we don't have
to watch the full podcast interview. So
now that we have the bare-bone clips,
I'm just going to go ahead and copy this
order over just because there's a lot
going on here, guys. And so I really
want to break this down for you guys
without having to create it from scratch
again. But basically, um since we're
working with a high project file, I do
want to mention that we need to go to
playback and turn our render cache on
smart because what's happening here is
our our tax ain't where our
computer will get taxed on. So you want
to make sure that you're utilizing your
space that you have on your MacBook,
right? So we're going to break the intro
down like the very beginning of part of
the intro down first things first. So
what we have going on here, we have a
lot going on. Wow, we need to really
section this out. I would want to say
that this is the first section, right?
Is clipping up the podcast, right? So in
this first section though, we have to
realize that there will be zooms that we
need to do. So right here when Copeland
says no, it doesn't say that, we're
cutting here, and as soon as he says it
doesn't say that, we're doing a punch in
on his face, right? It didn't even look
the cleanest, but I just thought it
looked good enough to use, right? Then
we're using a CRT flash overlay. So that
we we keep think we know that we're
going to do a zoom out. So instead of
just a boring uh going back to normal in
frame, we added a CRT overlay, which is
a really cool CRT effect. You can use
whatever CRT effect that you want to
use, but you're just going to add a CRT
effect.
Then if we go through this, he's
talking, and then right here, right when
Bryce is uh ending this off, I just used
some simple dynamic zoom, and then I go
ahead and use the linear. So we just use
this, and then boom, we fade it out, and
then we're good to go, right? Now song
also does play a choice into this, but
the thing is is song choice can really
just differentiate your video. But we're
not going to hop into the what you need
to do when it comes to choosing your
song type. Um but just know that it is
still very important aspect of the
actual video. So just make sure you
choose a good song. So now that we have
that section done, I want to go through
how I actually edit this, right? So if
we deactivate this adjustment layer,
you're going to notice that this is
where our zoom comes from, right? So
let's go ahead and break down this zoom.
It's really simple zoom. So how we get
this something like this is we're going
to come to effects page. We're going to
go to adjustment clip, and we're going
to drag down the adjustment clip, right?
And we really just need to bring it over
these two clips right here. And then
we're going to you can change the color
whatever you want to do, but we're going
to go into the fusion page with this
adjustment clip, and then we're going to
hit shift space for a transform node,
right? We're going to add this transform
node in. We're going to go to frame
zero. We're going to punch in
exponentially, probably at about like
three, and then hit a keyframe, and then
we're going to want to we're looking at
come at least 65 frames out into the
video, and then go back to the original
position. Now if you are familiar here,
this is an animation I teach often, so
we're going to hit right click all of
these animation points, and then go to
ease and go to out cubic, okay? Then
we're going to bring this down, and then
we're going to bring this one over here
just like this. So now we have that
animation that I used, and then we just
add the motion blur, and then we're good
to go. So now boom, we have the
animation, right? And sound effects also
do come into a play as well, but we
aren't really necessarily worried about
sound effects. So now what we need to
worry about is simply how I got this uh
this clean If you notice on the outside
edges, I have this blinking effect going
on, and this is a really good effect to
use to add depth in the video. So how I
did this is I went to the generators, I
grabbed a simple color, and I like to
make this stuff from scratch. So I'm
going to deactivate this by hitting D,
and then we're going to right click on
our keyboard. We're going to make this
as a new compound clip just like this.
We're going to go into the fusion page
with this compound clip. There's
probably such such a better way we could
have done this by just grabbing a
background layer and just dragging it on
just like that. But anyways, you could
do either way. But anyways, we're going
to add an ellipse tool, and then we're
going to drag this sucker like this.
We're basically going to create a
vignette, but we're going to invert it,
and then we're going to crank up the
soft edge.
Now you're probably wondering like why
didn't I just use a vignette? I would I
wanted to use my own and create my own
circle effect.
With this, you have more control over
where the circle goes, how the circle
goes. It's just more control. I like to
make things from scratch. But anyways,
we're going to do some simple opacity
tricks. We're going to hit the keyframe,
and go three frames forward, and crank
this up, go two frames forward, and then
crank it down just a little bit, two
frames forward, and kind of just repeat
this process until you are making this
like blinking effect. And when you pair
it up with this zoom out animation, it
just looks really good, right? And when
you add clean sound effects, then it
really starts to come into play, okay?
So now that we have the zoom out
animation going. So now that we have the
zoom out animation going, we really have
to get into the text animations, right?
So I'm going to keep it honest with you
guys. I do use these these preset packs
that I sell down below.
I didn't use anything other than my
preset packs. So we have Motion Text
Pro, and we have Motion Text Pro V2.
This is the original project file, by
the way. So this project file is exactly
what you're seeing is exactly what was
posted on his page. So as you can see, I
have this mash master bin, and we have
Motion Text Pro and Motion Text Pro V2,
which you can find on my website down
below. It is the best editing packs that
you can get for DaVinci Resolve. Took so
much time actually making these editing
packs, and it's literally just a
drag-and-drop workflow. So you can go
check those out on the first link in the
description. But essentially, we are
using these text animations. So how we
got this shine text effect was in Motion
Text Pro V1. So I'm going to go ahead
and deactivate this and show you guys
the actual effects that I was using. So
as you can see, this is the exact um
file or or text effect that we were
using. And as you can see, this is going
to look really chaotic, right? Because
it is. But the reality of it is is that
this is all just within my Motion Text
Pro V1. So we have this customization
where it comes up like this, right? Um
this is the text effect. We made the
text effect, but the shine text effect
is where it gets really tricky. So if
you guys want to go ahead and try to
recreate this, you can go ahead and just
literally just try to recreate this.
It's just as simple as putting this all
together. Um and then I obviously we
have so much more uh that goes into it,
and I'm going to show you guys how some
of these text effects actually work. But
um basically, we start off with this
first animation. It's hard for me to. So
I'm going to show you guys exactly how I
did that animation. We're not
gatekeeping anything around here. So
we're going to go ahead and go to the
effects and go to titles and drag down a
text plus, right? So what we used was
Helvetica, and we're using the font
bold. So it's hard for me to, okay?
We're going to side size this sucker
down, and the reason why I chose a black
color is because he has a white shirt,
and it's kind of like clashing with it.
So it's hard for me. And then this is a
good spot for that to come into, right?
So we're going to come and head into the
fusion page with this. And as you can
see, we have this going right here.
We're going to go to text, and we're
going to right click and go to follower,
okay? This is going to open up the
modifiers tab up here, okay? Then we
have our transform up here. We're going
to go to words, and on frame zero, we're
going to hit a keyframe on this offset.
Now it's going to put us away from the
follower, so we just have to double
click again, and then bring this sucker
down here just like so, probably like
negative 70 negative 0.078 is the sweet
spot.
And we're going to come approximately
like
20-ish frames forward, really just up to
you.
Um and then we're going to go back up to
zero, okay? We're going to open up a
spline page, and we're going to do the
same animation. So we're going to hit
command A, right click, ease out cubic,
right? And like I said, you guys don't
have to do this animation. You can go
ahead and cop the animation pack down
below. Um but if you guys wanted to
recreate this, this is how I did it. So
first we have that first animation pop
up. Now I'm going to show you guys how
we do it as the word for word. So that's
the first animation. So now what we have
to do is come to timing the delay. Now
this is where things get tricky, okay?
We're going to I really like one because
it's really slow. But as you could see,
now we we could see like what we're
working with here, and it looks really
weird.
What we could do is we could also just
do an opacity trick, come here, and go 1
2 3 4, and then just turn it back up,
right? But the problem with that is if
we play this through,
it looks like that, and I still think
that looks good, but as you could see,
you can see it just fading up, and I'm
not a huge fan of that. So I'm going to
command Z that actually, and we're going
to do a different way.
So [snorts] as you can see, we have the
font down here, and we know that it's
like down here. So what a good rule of
thumb is to realize that yo, if we just
throw a rectangle mask over this sucker,
and we go here, look at that. Boom, now
we have cut that out. And now look at
it. Just like that and now we don't have
that fade up. Now what we could do is
come to the soft edge and crank up the
soft edge a little bit. And then boom.
Now the only problem with that is we got
have this. So you could turn it down or
you can pull it up just a little bit.
But boom, that's exactly how we did
that. So it's hard for me to and then
we're going to reactivate this. So
So it's hard for me to but what I was
able to do was just come to Motion Text
Pro V1 and grab the text animation and
grab delay up slide. So if we go ahead
and check this sucker out
just like that. So it's
hard for me to size it down just like so
and then just change the color to black.
Just like that. Already done, right? And
so we're pretty much using the same
animations. We're just recycling them
throughout the whole video, right? So
it's hard for me to
And look at this. This idea. So if we go
ahead and replay this and we go ahead
and you could see that I I was
experimenting. So I was experimenting by
just using black but then I realized
that if we go ahead and add this blue
shine text effect, it really brings it
to life. And the video that Bryce had
sent me that he wanted me to replicate
off of was this blue shine text effect.
So we do that same animation just with
that shine text effect, which is a lot
more detailed. But you guys can
literally copy that exact workflow in
the fusion page or you can copy the
editing pack. But basically what we did
here is we we swipe up on our timeline
by holding shift and then scroll up on
our mouse. We have this faded out by
three frames on each time. So then you
could see it fades down. And then look
at this. We have another one popping up
at the same time. So we're being really
strategical. So this idea. So we have
the same exact thing.
>> [snorts]
>> Now this is where it gets really really
advanced. We go in and we zoom in on
this wall over here because I noticed
that in the example and I can show you
guys the example but he in the example
they would zoom in left and right left
and right left and right. Okay. So what
we have to do is we have to use the same
animation but just add a zoom in. So
what I have is this plugin called magic
zoom, okay? And magic zoom is a free
plugin. You can search it up online
whatever you want to do. It's not sold
by me. But basically magic zoom is a
simple plugin. You're just going to use
mirror and then it it's literally as
simple as a drag and drop situation. So
we're going to zoom in
on the left over here. But here's where
it gets tricky because most people don't
know this. You have to keep your magic
zoom above everything else. So if we
look at this, the text effects are below
the magic zoom. And the reason why is
because look at this.
If we just did that without the zoom, it
would have not looked anything like what
it should look like, right? So God wants
everyone to be wealthy. We really got to
break this one down because this where's
a lot going on here. But we will get
there. So first things first, we're
going to go frame by frame. We have that
same animation that I just taught you.
And then what we have is this underline
come through and a money effect. So
you're probably wondering how I got this
money effect. All I did was I went on
YouTube and I found a free money
overlay. And then I'm going to
deactivate all of this so I can show you
guys exactly how I did this. But if we
just play the money overlay, this is
what it looks like.
So I'm going to actually right click and
you're going to see this overlay that I
did. So what I did was I hit command R
and I have this regular speed come out.
But if I go ahead and I clear this speed
point and then I change the speed back
to 100, look at how long the clip is.
Like it takes forever for it to fall out
and then it wouldn't make any sense. So
what I did was I added what's called a
speed point. So you add a speed point by
right clicking on these black arrows and
then you add a speed point. Then what we
did was we sped it up by holding this
and just dragging it just like so. And
then we come up to the keyframes. We go
to the zoom to fit and then it brings up
the keyframe editor. And as you could
see, we just smooth this sucker out.
That way it does not a harsh cut. So
that's how we did that. We're going to
hit command R, get rid of that. Okay.
And then you're probably wondering how
we got it overlaid. All you got to do is
add scan lines into your timeline and
then you're good to go.
And then just change the color to green.
That way like you know, it has that cool
effect to it. Now we're like, yo, how do
we get Bryce behind us because if it
went like this, it wouldn't make sense
also. So what I had to do was I had to
put the money below the text and also
below Bryce. So how we did this was we
right click and we make this as another
clip. So what we do is we hold option
and we can scroll up just like this to
make a second copy. And what we do with
this second copy is we're going to come
into the fusion page. And what we're
going to do is this this this tool
called magic mask. And what it does is
it essentially just auto masks out the
subject, which is exactly what we want.
So we auto masked out the subject and
then we put the money behind him. It's
as simple as that, guys. I mean, come
on. So now we have that same animation.
Literally look. If we literally turn off
all these effects,
same animation. And then this is where
it gets snazzy because we add this
underline effect. And you're probably
wondering how the heck do we do that?
I hate to say it, guys, but this is also
in Motion Text Pro V2. If we come down
to graphics and then you go ahead and go
to the underline. Where is the
underline? We got line one. So all we
got to do is drag this onto the
timeline. And then as you can see, it
automatically animates for us. And then
the best part about this is you can go
to the fusion page and these are all
handmade in DaVinci Resolve. You can
come to background and then change the
color to whatever you want, which is
super lit in my new Motion Text Pro V2
pack. I hate plugging these plat packs
but this is genuinely how I made the
edit. And this is how and I this is me
breaking it down. So we just do that
same animation just like so. We have
wealthy and then we underline the
wealthy cuz how we underline it, we took
that underline and then we just move the
position to where it goes right under
wealthy just like so.
And then we reuse that cycle that same
animation, healthy, but we're doing it
coming in right. And then
then when we enter in Copeland, we use a
different color. So Bryce is supposedly
like the good guy, right? That's the
whole point of the podcast or whatever
you wanted it to be like. But we have to
change good guy good good guy or bad guy
whatever it is, we have to change up the
caption style because he is a different
character. So we have to add diversity.
So the diversity is just changing the
color to red. So we just use the same
animations just like this. Look at this.
Boom.
Just in red.
So as you see, I
all this is the same animation just
using that fade in out all that other
tactics. And then we have a flicker
effect just like this as I mentioned,
which then comes back into the zoom out,
right? Then we're going to zoom in on
his right side. So this is what I'm
saying. Like you have to be strategic
when it comes to the edit because if I
went to his left side, then it would
have been just only going to the left
side. The viewers want to be being taken
to all over different places of the
edit. So I wanted to take them over to
the right side mainly because of how
valuable it is to change angles because
you don't want the audience to be
looking at the same left corner. So
[snorts] we move to the right corner,
right? Which was tricky because you can
see we have less space over here. So
what I did was I really punched in. So I
really punched in that way we have this
room right below the picture frame. And
then we're being bringing in this being
rich just like this. Same animations. So
we're recycling the same animations.
We're just using them in different ways.
But rich since it is a
since it has the same shine effect, we
have to
um
since it's talking about money, we have
to use the green in this case. That just
made more sense. But I'm going to go
over how I did this flicker money effect
and then also how I got this airplane.
So stay tuned.
So we added another flicker effect,
being rich, and then we added the
flicker effect. So I really want to
break this down. Let's actually take
this out. So first of all, we got the
zoom, magic zoom, which by the way, I
could show you guys how to do really
quickly in case if you guys don't know
how to do that. It's the same thing.
We're going to come up to the adjustment
clip just like so. And we're going to go
ahead into the fusion page with this
adjustment clip and then hit shift space
for a transform node. We're going to hit
a keyframe on this frame right here.
We're going to go in to about frame 35,
which is where we want the animation to
end. We're going to then zoom in just
like so.
Actually that is a little too much
zoomed in. But basically just bring it
to the position that you want it to be
in basically. So we want it to be right
about here. Now we have these
animational points just like so. Now
here's where it gets tricky. So we have
the same points. We're going to hit
command A, right click, ease out cubic.
We want to have these animations do the
same thing. So we're going to grab these
two points and we're going to drag them
up at least try to get them as identical
as possible ideally. Then drag these
two.
And then we're going to bring this one
straight just like so.
Just like so. And then kind of just
playing around with the animation really
at this point. And then if we look at it
So that's what also where it comes like
you can play around with this animation
and make your own curves.
So what we could do is only bring this
animation in just like that. Boom. Comes
in really fast, right? So really just
play around with those keyframes. But
this is why I use magic mask which or
magic zoom, sorry. But this is why you
also should use Motion Text Pro V2. Like
why would you even want to mess with it
in Motion Text Pro V1 because you have
the effects already done for you, right?
So
>> [snorts]
>> So we have this animation come in first.
So being it comes up just like this. And
then rich comes in right here. It comes
in and it animates
left. Okay. And then we have this glitch
effect. So I'm going to actually
deactivate all of these so you guys can
see what's going on here. So the reason
why I have these
these these money signs and how they're
hollow is by using a font. So if we go
ahead and do this from scratch, I'm
going to come to the text font. We're
going to type a couple of money signs
in. And then we're going to do tactic
sands. So as you can see, if we find the
right one, come to shading, enable the
hollow point just like that. Then we're
going to head into the fusion page with
this.
And then we're going to simply change
the color to that green, just like so.
And then we are going to hit shift space
for a soft glow, and then we're going to
add this to this effect, and then we're
going to mess around with the soft glow.
Kind of turn up the gain just like so,
turn down the gain just like that. Looks
really clean. Now we're going to come to
the template and we're going to right
click and go to follower. We're going to
go to modifiers, we're going to go to
shading, and this is where the opacity
trick will come into play. We're going
to turn the opacity all the way down,
key frame it just like so, bring it up
just a little bit, and then come up just
a little bit, bring it down. Kind of
create this flicker effect, but I'm
going to show you guys how we did it in
per per thing. So, right now we have
this, which looks good already. Um and
if you wanted to, you can keep it at
that. Now we just have to turn on the
delay, and as you can see, now we have
that flicker effect and it looks super
lit. So, that's how we were able to do
that. And then now if you're probably
wondering why mine looks a little better
is because we did another masking out
trick. So, we grab this mask and we're
going to bring it just like so, and
we're going to invert it. And then we're
going to crank up the soft edge just
like so. And then as you can see, this
is going to create this diversity of
like a soft smooth in effect just like
so.
Just like that, and it looks super lit,
and that's how we did that effect. So,
if we play this through, boom.
And then we add this in, we add this in,
and we add this in, and then we finally
add the zoom in. We have more than
enough, which is just if we look at more
than enough. What we did was instead of
using bold, we used light. We just used
Helvetica light, simple as that, sized
it down, put it right below it. So, now
you're probably wondering how the heck
we got this airplane animation. So, I'm
going to show you guys exactly how I did
this. So, I did not use any VFX, I did
use some
masking out tricks, obviously. But
basically, I found this actually on
Instagram.
I found this on YouTube, which is kind
of crazy. But if we go to the fusion
page, I have this delta keyer. So, if I
take out this delta keyer, you can see
it's just a green screen, just like
this, and I found this on YouTube and it
looks really slow and it's really
boring. So, we're going to add a delta
keyer, and then we're going to grab
this, and then just easy enough,
come to the
gain and kind of just turn it down to,
you know, smooth it up. Boom, simple as
that, right? But it's not. So, we hit
right click, and as you can see, we have
the same speed points. So, we have it
speed in really fast. We're just like
this. So, we had the speed at 1,274,
and then we slow it down just like this,
back to 100, and then we we smooth it
out really fast when we don't want it
there anymore. Okay, it's as simple as
that. So, now I'm going to come back to
timeline one, and then as you see, it
goes
behind him. And how we did that was we
simply just
we simply just masked out Copeland just
like we did with Bryce in the beginning
with magic masks. So, so if we just look
at this, we're really just using the
same motion text pro animations. And
that's pretty much exactly how I was
able to create this podcast intro,
literally just using the same properties
throughout the whole rest of the video.
And even if this seems foreign to you,
like just know that I have like 6 years
of video editing experience. Once I
created this pack for me to drag and
drop, if I could show you guys, like I
can't stress this enough how
informational this pack is. Because we
have all these animations, like all
these other animations, like we even
have the Sean Shine text effect and
everything, right? Like we have all
these animations for you to use, and the
best part is is we have these things
called hook styles. And so, what these
hook styles do is there are hooks that
you can just literally copy and paste.
So, this hook you can literally just
copy and paste. Now, in this case, I did
not use that in the Copeland interview
because this needed more tailored
specific, but these are for short form
content editors, but my packs are for
any editor in general. If you guys
really enjoyed this, then please just
leave a subscribe, and it would it would
really help me. And also, don't forget
to check out motion text pro V1 and V2.
Literally just hit the subscribe button
because I will be posting more bangers
just like this, and I will see you guys
in the next video.